Finding Aid for the Evelyn Caldwell Hooker Papers LSC.0523
UCLA Library Special Collections
Evelyn Caldwell Hooker papers
1910-1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hooker, Evelyn Caldwell, 1907-1996
LSC.0523
9.5 linear feet (13 boxes, 2 cartons, and 1 oversize box)
Evelyn Gentry (1907-1996) was born in North Platte, Nebraska, and grew up near Sterling, Colorado. She joined the psychology faculty at UCLA University Extension in 1939. In 1954, she received a grant from the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) for a comparative study of the pathology of homosexual and heterosexual males. In 1970, she retired from UCLA and began private practice as a psychotherapist. The collection consists of publications, manuscripts, correspondence, books, lectures and speeches, biographical materials, obituary and memorial tributes, diplomas and certificate, awards, appointment calendars, photographs, memorabilia, and the American Psychological Foundation 1991-93 annual report.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joseph Carrier, 1996.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942331633606533
Biography
Evelyn Gentry was born on September 2, 1907 in North Platte, Nebraska, and grew up near Sterling, Colorado; awarded bachelor's and master's degrees in psychology from University of Colorado; Ph.D in psychology, Johns Hopkins University; joined psychology faculty at UCLA University Extension in 1939; after her marriage to Donn Caldwell, she married UCLA English professor Edward Niles Hooker in 1951; in 1954 she received a grant from the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) for a comparative study of the pathology of homosexual and heterosexual males; her 1957 paper, The Adjustment of the Male Overt Homosexual, reported little statistical difference; chaired NIMH Task Force on Homosexuality in 1967, which issued what came to be called the Hooker Report in 1969; retired from UCLA in 1970, and began private practice as a psychotherapist; awarded the Distinguished Contributions to Psychology career achievement award from the American Psychological Association in 1992; in the same year, she chaired the establishment of the Wayne Placek Fund, an endowment administered by the American Psychological Foundation to support research in homosexuality; she died on November 18, 1996 in Santa Monica, California.
Expanded Biographical Narrative
Evelyn Hooker was born Evelyn Gentry in North Platte, Nebraska on 2 September 1907 and grew up near Sterling, Colorado. She earned bachelor's and master's degrees in psychology from the University of Colorado and a Ph.D. in psychology at The Johns Hopkins University. She joined the Psychology faculty of the University Extension at the University of California, Los Angeles in 1939. Following her marriage to Donn Cadwell, she was married to Edward Niles Hooker, an English literature professor at UCLA, from 1951 until his death in 1951.
In 1954, Hooker received a grant from the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) to conduct a comparative study of the pathology of homosexual and heterosexual males. Her controversial 1957 paper, The Adjustment of the Male Overt Homosexual, reported little statistical difference in the test results of the two groups of subjects. By the late 1960s Hooker was recognized as an authority in the psychology of homosexual behavior. In 1967 she the NIMH Task Force on Homosexuality which in 1969 issued what came to be referred to as the Hooker Report.
Dr. Hooker retired from UCLA in 1970 and entered private practice as a psychotherapist. She received numerous awards and honors from professional societies, such as the Distinguished Contributions to Psychology career achievement award in 1992 from the American Psychological Association, as well as gay and lesbian organizations, including serving as grand marshal of the Christopher Street West Gay Pride Parade in 1986. In 1992 she chaired the establishment of the Wayne Placek Fund, an endowment administered by the American Psychological Foundation to support research in homosexuality. The 1993 film, Changing Our Minds: The Story of Dr. Evelyn Hooker, received a nomination as Best Documentary Feature by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. Evelyn Hooker died on November 18, 1996 at her home in Santa Monica, California.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of publications, manuscripts, correspondence, books, lectures and speeches, biographical materials, obituary and memorial tributes, diplomas and certificate, awards, appointment calendars, photographs, memorabilia, and the American Psychological Foundation 1991-93 annual report.
Expanded Scope and Content
The papers of Evelyn Hooker span the years 1910-1997. Included are obituaries and memorials, photographs, correspondence, manuscripts, lectures, publications, newspaper and magazine clippings, tributes and awards, and autographed and inscribed books which offer a very incomplete Her personal and family life are highlighted by material from her high school yearbook and material about her husband, Edward Niles Hooker. A partial set of publications and manuscripts include many popular press items which are not listed on her curriculum vitae, which focuses on her handful of peer-reviewed publications. Manuscripts of lectures and speeches derive mostly from the 1980s; several were written as long acceptance remarks and commentaries upon the receipt of some of her many awards and honors. Almost all the photographs are snapshot portraits of Hooker and her friends (including Joseph Carrier, David Haugland, and her Cabinet: Linda Garnets, Jackie Goodchilds, and Anne Peplau) throughout the 1990s. The correspondence, though sparse, is supplemented by a large number of autographed monographs, many with long inscriptions. The most notable lacunae in this collection are Hooker's research and patient notes, which she promised her subjects and patients she would shred; she followed through on her promise in the 1980s.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Obituaries and memorial tributes.
Autobiographical and biographical material.
Education and licensure.
Family.
Photographs.
Tributes and awards.
Lectures and speeches.
Manuscripts.
Publications.
Correspondence.
Wayne Placek Fund.
Appointment calendars.
Information files.
Books.
Hooker, Edward Niles
- Obituaries and Memorial Tributes
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Death certificate, 1996.; (Photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Obituaries and tributes, 1996-1997. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Celebration of the life of Evelyn Hooker, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    General note
    Memorial service at UCLA Faculty Center, December 20, 1996; programs and audiocassette tape.
    - Celebration of the Life of Evelyn Hooker-Memorial Service at UCLA, 1996 December 20; yrlsc_0523_001_003a; 1 sound recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:30:58) (Box 1, Case 3)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
      Scope and Contents
      Transcribed from container: Celebration of the Life of Evelyn Hooker, UCLA Faculty Center; December 20, 1996; Joseph Carrier, Edwin Shneirdman, Judd Marmor, Letitia Ann Peplau, Gregory Herek, David Haugland.
    - Celebration of the Life of Evelyn Hooker-Memorial Service at UCLA, 1996 December 20; yrlsc_0523_001_003b; 1 sound recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:30:56) (Box 1, Case 3)
- Autobiographical and Biographical Material
  - Evelyn Caldwell Hooker bookplate, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Published interviews with Evelyn Hooker and popular press reviews and mentions of her work, 1960-1992. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Evelyn Hooker letterhead stationery, ca. 1970s-1996. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum vitae (Manuscript), 1980. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Driver's license, 1989-1993. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Education and Licensure
  - Diplomas (A.B., M.A., Ph.D.), 1928-1932. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Certified Psychologist certificate (California), 1958. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Family
  - Edward Niles Hooker's family birth dates, entered in: Longfellow Birthday Book, 1910. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tiger (photocopy; incomplete), 1924. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    High school yearbook; includes entries for Evelyn Hooker (Evelyn Gentry) and her sisters Jewel and Mildred; includes photograph of Evelyn Hooker with Debating team. Original in possession of Mildred Gentry.
  - High school yearbook autograph pages for Mildred Gentry (holographs), ca. 1924. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Postal cover addressed to Evelyn Hooker from Donn Caldwell, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Edward Niles Hooker, UCLA 32nd Annual Faculty Research Lecturer (program), 1956. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Edward Niles Hooker, In Memoriam (biographical memorial), 1958. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Memorial service program for Ralph E. Gentry (1903-1972) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs
  - Photograph of Matthew and Elizabeth Spender, 1953. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of Evelyn Hooker and unidentified man on Evelyn C. Hooker's trip to China (People-to-People Mental Health Delegation), 1983. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, ca. 1983-1996. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Andy Boxer and Monte Hetland; Chicago, ca. 1983 (2 photos). (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Andy Boxer, Gilbert Herdt, and Evelyn C. Hooker; Chicago, ca. 1983. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Evelyn Hooker and her Cabinet: Anne Peplau, Jackie Goodchilds, and Linda Garnets; Santa Monica, 1990s (2 photos). (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Ruby Takaneshi and family, 1990s(?) (2 photos). (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Anne Peplau, Evelyn C. Hooker, and Gregory Herek; Santa Monica, 1990s. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Andy Boxer and Joe Carrier, ca. 1993. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - David Hoagland, Joe Carrier, Russell Boxley, Beth Meyerowitz,and Evelyn C. Hooker; Santa Monica, December 1994. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Joe Carrier, David Hoagland, Ted [?], Evelyn C. Hooker, and Beth Meyerowitz; Santa Monica, December 1995. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Paul Franklin; Los Angeles, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Evelyn C. Hooker; Santa Monica, December 1995. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Andy Boxer and Monte Hedland and their flower garden; Chicago, 1996 (4 photos). (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - - Evelyn Hooker in her study; Santa Monica, ca. 1996 (3 photos). (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Evelyn Hooker Amanda Boxley; Santa Monica (19 photos), ca. 1993, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photograph of unidentified man, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Tributes and Awards
  - Hardly a backward glance: response to The Distinguished Contributions Award--American Psychological Association, Division 12/Division of Clinical Psychology (newsletter), 1975. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Award of Merit--Prosperos (plaque), 1976. (Box 14)
  - Woman of the Year--Christopher Street West (plaque), 1976. (Box 14)
  - Integrity Award--Integrity, Incorporated, Gay Episcopalians and their Friends (diploma), 1980. (Box 15)
  - Distinguished Award for Scientific Contribution in the Public Interest--Group Psychotherapy Association of Southern California, Incorporated (plaque), 1981. (Box 15)
  - Scientific Achievement in Psychology Recognition--California State Psychological Association (plaque), 1981. (Box 14)
  - Annual Awards Banquet--Bay Area Physicians for HumanRights (round silver-plated tray), 1982. (Box 15)
  - Honorary Life Membership--Bay Area Physicians for Human Rights (plaque), 1983. (Box 14)
  - Archangel Awards--Dignity, Los Angeles (diploma), 1984. (Box 15)
  - Meritorious Service Award--Society for the Scientific Study of Sex, Incorporated, Eastern Region (plaque), 1985. (Box 14)
  - Grand Marshal, Gay Pride Parade--Christopher Street West(newspaper clipping), 1986. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Grand Marshal, Gay Pride Celebration--Christopher Street West/Los Angeles (plaque), 1986. (Box 14)
  - Recognition--Committee on Lesbian and Gay Concerns of the American Psychological Association (plaque), 1986. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Perfect 10 Award--Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays, 1986. (Box 14)
  - Michael Lonergan Memorial Award--Long Beach Lambda Democratic Club (plaque), 1987. (Box 14)
  - Morris Kight Humanitarian Award--The Los Angeles Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center (lucite triangle and base), 1989. (Box 14)
  - Distinguished Service Award--The Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychiatrists (newsletter), 1990. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Distinguished Service Award--The Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychiatrists (plaque), 1990. (Box 14)
  - Distinguished Contributions to Psychology in the Public Interest Career Award--American Psychological Association (diploma), 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - GLMA Achievement Award--The Gay and Lesbian Medical Association (round silver-plated tray), 1995. (Box 14)
- Lectures and Speeches
  - The Homosexual Community (Typescript), 1961. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Mental Health of Homosexuals: Implications for Therapy (abstract in: Journal: People-to-People Mental Health Delegation to the People's Republic of China), 1983. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - GAU [Gay Academic Union] featured speaker (program), 1984. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - I'm just trying to get through 1984! Progress in the 20th century (Manuscript), ca. 1984. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - My Own [Experience], 1944-1984: 40 years as Researcher and Friend of the Gay Community (Manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The changing status of gays and lesbians: 1954-1985 (Manuscript, typescript) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Address by Evelyn Hooker: Distinguished Award for Psychology in the Public Interest--American Psychological Association (Typescript), 1992. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Challenge and Opportunity of the Gay Health Crisis, i.e. Aids [sic] or sex + love (Manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Functions of Psychiatry in Society (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Homophobia in the 1980s (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - My Fear of Confidentiality (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Politics of Diagnosis (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Understanding gay & lesbian lifestyles (Manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Untitled notes (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Untitled notes (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Manuscripts
  - Notes and correspondence re: book reviews, 1962, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - An Empirical Study of Some Relations Between Sexual Patterns and Gender Identity in Male Homosexuals (Typescript), published 1965. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Epilogue ( JSI) (Typescript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Manuscript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Publications
  - The Behavior of White Rats Under Food and Electric Shock Stimulation by Knight Dunlap, Evelyn Gentry and Thornton W. Zeigler (offprint), 1931. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Methods of Discrimination Training in White Rats by Evelyn Gentry (offprint), 1934. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Adjustment of the Male Overt Homosexual by Evelyn Hooker (photocopy), 1957. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - A Life to Live and a Job to Do (article in issue of California Librarian), 1957. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Male Homosexuality in the Rorschach (offprints), 1958. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Psychological Aspects of the Mediation Process (article in issue of Labor Law Journal), 1958. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Still Some Doubt in Lesbos (book review; tearsheet), 1958. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes Evelyn C. Hooker's review copy, with marginalia, of Richard C. Robertiello's Voyage from Lesbos (with dust jacket).
  - What is a Criterion? (offprint), 1959. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Discussion in: The Prediction of Overt Behavior Through the Use of Projective Techniques (book, with dust jacket), 1960. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Fable (offprint), 1960. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Case of El: A Biography in: The Case of El: A Demonstration of Diagnostic Methods in Clinical Psychology (offprints and entire report), 1961. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Homosexual Community (offprints), 1961. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Homosexuality-Summary of Studies (photocopy), 1961. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Male Homosexual Lifestyles and Venereal Disease (photocopy), 1962. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Male Homosexuality in: Taboo Topics (chapter in monograph, with dust jacket), 1963. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Adjustment of the Overt Male Homosexual Community in: The Problem of Homosexuality in Modern Society (chapter in monograph, with dust jacket), 1963. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Male Homosexuals and Their 'Worlds' (chapter in monograph; offprint), 1965. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Homosexual Community (photocopy), 1966. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Homosexual Community in: Sexual Deviance (chapter in paperback monograph), 1967. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Homosexuality in: International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (offprints), 1968. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Final Report of the Task Force on Homosexuality [The Hooker Report] in: Homophile Studies no. 22 (issue of serial), 1969. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Parental Reactions and Male Homosexuality in Patient and Nonpatient Samples (photocopy), 1969. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence
  - ACLUF [American Civil Liberties Union Foundation], 1990. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes copy of Epidemic of fear: A survey of AIDS discrimination in the 1980s and policy recommendations for the 1990s.
  - Bachardy, Don, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bell, Richard Q., 1960. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Benjamin, Harry, 1966. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Boxer, Andrew M., 1993. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Boxley, Russell L., 1973. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Author's autograph Typescript of his thesis, Sex-object choice in adult black males.
  - Cody, John V., 1996. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Includes: author's autograph Typescript of his Some notes on Dr. Evelyn Hooker's Value-Conflict and Value-Congruence of a Homosexual Group in a Heterosexual Society by Gerald Heard.
  - Cohen, Joseph W., 1990. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - From, Isadore, 1955. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Gagnon, John H., 1964-1967. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes preprints and offprints of his articles, 1955-1967.
  - Harrison, James [Intelligence in Media, Incorporated], 1987. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hitchcock, Charles G., 1972-1973. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Includes: Typescript draft of his Psychiatric Attitudes Towards Homosexuality.
  - Kaye, Alan, ca. 1953. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Journal of Psychiatric Research [Robert Maxwell], 1961. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Herek, Gregory M., ca. 1977, 1996. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Kerr, Clark, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Typewritten letters addressed to Mrs. Evelyn Hooker.
  - Köhler, Wolfgang, 1941. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Autographed letters to Karl F. Muenzinger.
  - Kramer, Harry P., 1982, 1984. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lunde, Donald T., 1975. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - McGraw-Hill, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Meyerowitz, Beth E., 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Michels, Bernard, 1976. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newsweek (Bruce Shenitz), 1990. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Oberstone, Andrea Kincses, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Her autographed Ph.D. thesis: Dimensions of Psychological Adjustment and Style of Life in Single Lesbians and Single Heterosexual Women (E. Hooker, Dissertation Committee Chair, California School of Professional Psychology).
  - Rhoads, Allan Harry, 1982. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    His inscribed (to Russell Boxley) Ph.D. thesis: Personality characteristics of single and coupled male homosexuals (E. Hooker, Dissertation Committee member, California School of Professional Psychology).
  - Ruddick, Ron W., 1986. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sapir, Philip [The Grant Foundation], 1969, 1971. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Schiller, Gregory C., 1980. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Shively, Michael G., 1977. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    His (with James R. Rudolph) autographed M.A. thesis: The Identification of Social Sex-Role Stereotypes.
  - Silverstein, Charles, ca. 1977, 1986. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes photograph of Silverstein, ca. 1977.
  - Southern Poverty Law Center (Montgomery, Alabama), 1995. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Spender, Natasha, 1996. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Includes: Memorial service propram for Sir Stephen Spender (1909-1995).
  - Sperber, Laurence R., 1983. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Includes amicus curiae brief in which Evelyn Hooker joined: State of New York vs. Robert Uplinger (U.S. Supreme Court, 82-1724).
  - Wagner, Richard, 1980. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Weitzman, Marcia, 1981. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Her M.A. thesis, dedicated to Evelyn C. Hooker: Homosexuality as viewed from five perspectives: The child, the parents, the family, the counselor, the community---An informational handbook (California State University, Northridge).
  - Wolff, Charlotte, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1967-1995. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    This folder contains a card from Chuck (Charles D.) Rowland, one of the founders of the Mattachine Society, a gay rights organization.
  - Unsolicited query, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Evelyn C. Hooker's Christmas card register, 1955-1962. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Wayne Placek Fund (American Psychological Foundation)
  - Press release: APF receives Wayne Placek Trust: $510,000 for research on gay men and lesbians, (?)., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - American Psychological Foundation 1991-1993 annual report (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence re Wayne Placek Fund, 1993-1996. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Appointment Calendars
  - Week-at-a-Glance appointment calendars, 1972-1994. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Includes: 1972-1979, 1989, 1992-1994.
- Information Files
  - An introduction to the Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory (mimeographed typescript), 1954. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Biography and notes on Henry A. Murray (annotated typescript) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Non-Parametric Methods: The Mann-Whitney Technique (U-Test) (mimeographed Typescript), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Books
  - Inscriptions and title pages (photocopies) of Evelyn C. Hooker-owned books which were incorporated into the general UCLA collections, 1938-1986. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Covers (photocopies) of Evelyn C. Hooker-owned serials which were transferred to UCLA Department of Special Collections' Gay and Lesbian Studies Collections, 1954-1981. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - ORION (UCLA libraries' online public access catalog) catalog records for which uninscribed, unannotated Evelyn C. Hooker-owned books duplicated library holdings and were returned to donor, 1936-1982. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Inscriptions and title pages (copies) and ORION catalog records for which inscribed Evelyn C. Hooker-owned books duplicated library holdings and were returned to donor, 1928-1978. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Books not previously owned by UCLA libraries, 1925-1982. (Box 9)
    - Allen, David L. The Light from the Second Story Window. New York: Exposition Press, c. 1972. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 9)
    - Allport, Gordon W. and Floyd H. Allport. The A-S Reaction Study: A Scale for Measuring Ascending Ascendance-Submission in Personality. Manual of Directions, Scoring Values, and Norms. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company, c. 1939. (Box 9)
    - Bauer, Helen. Hawaii, the Aloha State. Garden City, New York: Doubleday & Company, c. 1960. [Author's autograph presentation copy, 1976]. (Box 9)